Guide to the Stephan Loewentheil photograph collection, 1822-1979.
Loewentheil, Stephan photograph collection
- Series VIII. Edward Curtis: Native Americans and The West, 1925; Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1952; 17 x 14 in (43.2 x 35.6 cm); 15 plates (Box VIII-1-4)
  - Calf child - Blackfoot, Mounted in custom lightbox by collector for exhibition. (Box VIII-4)
Notables: "English Society: The Van Der Weyer Family Album, Camille Silvy Photographs" (CDV 46), 8043 Bd. Ms. 22++
Medical: "Patients and Physicians of Chriton Institute" (CDV 33), 8043 Bd. Ms. 23+
Scientists: "Architects, Engineers & Scientists" (CDV 65), 8043 Bd. Ms. 24++
Scientists: "Scientists" (plus 11 cabinet cards) (CDV 67), 8043 Bd. Ms. 25++
Royalty: "Queen Victoria & the Royal Family" (CDV 60), 8043 Bd. Ms. 26++
Notables: European Law (barristers, judges, lawyers-plus 10 cabinets), brass album with red stones and single brass clasp (CDV 50), 8043 Bd. Ms. 27+
Notables: European Royalty & Notables (plus 8 cabinet cards), brown album with single brass clasp (CDV 51), 8043 Bd. Ms. 28++ v. 1
Notables: Europeans Notables (plus 6 cabinets), red album with single brass clasp (CDV 52), 8043 Bd. Ms. 28++ v. 2
Ecclesiastic: (plus 6 cabinets), brown album w/ brass edge and single brass clasp (CDV 59), 8043 Bd. Ms. 29++
Royalty: Royalty from Belgium, Denmark, China, Turkey, England, etc., large green album (CDV 61), 8043 Bd. Ms. 30++ v. 1
Royalty: Royalty from Italy, Spain, etc., plus 26 cabinets (CDV 62), 8043 Bd. Ms. 30++ v. 2
Royalty: Royalty, carved wooden album (CDV 63), 8043 Bd. Ms. 30++ v. 3
Photographs of New York State Assembly officials (Boss Tweed and New York State government), 8043 Bd. Ms. 31++ v. 1
Photographs of New York State Assembly officials (Album of the Assembly), 8043 Bd. Ms. 31++ v. 2
Photographs of New York State Assembly officials (New York State Assembly), 8043 Bd. Ms. 31++ v. 3
Judiciary Committee of the Constitutional Convention of the State of New York, 8043 Bd. Ms. 32+
New York album, 8043 Bd. Ms. 33
Cameron: "Julia Margaret Cameron" (CDV 20), 8043 Bd. Ms. 34+
India: "Haji Abbas Ali: Historical Album of The Rajas & Taaluqdars of Oudh" (CDV 31), 8043 Bd. Ms. 35
Hartford: "Hartford Family Album" (CDV 28), 8043 Bd. Ms. 36 tiny
Sideshow: "Circus & Sideshow" (CDV 68), 8043 Bd. Ms. 37
Scientists & Artists: "A Notebook of W. F. Ecroyd" (CDV 64), 8043 Bd. Ms. 38
Presidents: "Presidents" (of the United States) (CDV 57), 8043 Bd. Ms. 39
Notables: "Important & Interesting by Brady, Disderi & Others" (CDV 49), 8043 Bd. Ms. 40
Twain: "Mark Twain Album" (CDV 69), 8043 Bd. Ms. 41 v. 1
Twain: "Samuel Clemens Family Album - CDV Signed by Twain" (CDV 70), 8043 Bd. Ms. 41 v. 2
Twain: "Samuel Clemens Family Album" (CDV 71), 8043 Bd. Ms. 41 v. 3
American: small black album (plus 6 tintypes) (CDV 74), 8043 Bd. Ms. 42 tiny v. 2
American: small brown album (CDV 75), 8043 Bd. Ms. 42 tiny v. 3
Notables: "American and European Notables" (CDV 41), 8043 Bd. Ms. 43 v. 1
Notables: "American Notables" (CDV 42), 8043 Bd. Ms. 43 v. 2
Cartes de visite of Union generals and children (Civil War, General Nathaniel Banks album, CDV 77), 8043 Bd. Ms. 44+ v. 1
Cartes de visite of Union generals and children (Union generals, CDV 15), 8043 Bd. Ms. 44+ v. 2(
Notables: "English & Europeans Royalty & Notables" (CDV 44), 8043 Bd. Ms. 45+ v. 1
Notables: "English & European Notables" (CDV 45), 8043 Bd. Ms. 45+ v. 2
Dickens Family Album, 8043 Bd. Ms. 46
Massachusetts: "Massachusetts Senate" (CDV 32), 8043 Bd. Ms. 47+
Military: "Ecole Speciale Militaire De St. Cyr" (CDV 35), 8043 Bd. Ms. 48+
European:: A European Album, small brown album (CDV 38), 8043 Bd. Ms. 49 tiny v. 1
European: An English Album (CDV 39), 8043 Bd. Ms. 49 tiny v. 2
Notables: European Notables, red album (CDV 76), 8043 Bd. Ms. 50
Youth: Children, Adolescents and Circus Personalities (CDV 72), 8043 Bd. Ms. 51
Medical: "Physicians" (and Scientists) (CDV 34), 8043 Bd. Ms. 52
Souvenir De St. Lazare (CDV 40), 8043 Bd. Ms. 53 tiny
Paris: "Paris Album, Exposition Universelle" (CDV 54), 8043 Bd. Ms. 54
Civil War medicine cartes de visite (CDV 22), 8043 Bd. Ms. 55
Cartes de visite of Lincoln and his generals (Civil War carte de visite photographs, Lincoln and his generals, CDV 23), 8043 Bd. Ms. 56 tiny
Civil War cartes de visite (Abraham Lincoln and portraits of the Civil War years, CDV 21), 8043 Bd. Ms. 57 v. 1
Civil War cartes de visite (Civil War, Charles A. Fisk album), 8043 Bd. Ms. 57 v. 2
Abraham Lincoln ambrotypes and tintype, 8043 Bd. Ms. 58+
Notables: "An American Album" (CDV 43), 8043 Bd. Ms. 59
American: American Album (plus 28 cabinet size photographs), no cover or back (CDV 36), 8043 Bd. Ms. 60+
Hay: "John Hay Album" (CDV 29), 8043 Bd. Ms. 61
Regional: Unusual Wooden Display Box With Pull Out Racks, Featuring British and Native Portraits (CDV 58), 8043 Bd. Ms. 62+++
Varia: Brown Wooden Box, top reads "Photographs" (CDV 37), 8043 Bd. Ms. 63+++
New York tunnel extension of the Pennsylvania Railroad, 8043 Bd. Ms. 64+++
Class 1857, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 8043 Bd. Ms. 65+
Charles Dickens letter to Monsieur Silvy, 8043 Bd. Ms. 66
Engineering album of subway tunnels and bridges under construction, 8043 Bd. Ms. 67+